Translation: honest bean paste bag WILDERBEAST sixteen Philippine sun Sao Deng Rosa MarsForever
Proofreading: Mahsele Zhang Sixteen Rosa Honest Bean Paste Bun
Shaft\Pressure: HollaBella Machsel Zhang
Welcome to follow Sina Weibo @马赫塞勒张 to get the video download address with embedded Chinese and English subtitles and translator annotations
The translations used in this subtitle when referring to the original text of the "Bible" are based on the "Mandarin Chinese Union Version" ("God" version)
The Psychological Significance of the Story of the Bible, Lecture 4 Adam and Eve-Self-awareness of Evil and Death by Jordan B. Peterson
Hello everyone
Hope we can today
Finish the content of the first chapter of "Genesis"
That's probably what I planned
I finished my new book yesterday
It took me three years to finish this book
It’s a long time for writing
In short, it's finished
There is still the final finishing work
Some copy editing, etc. Hope it will go smoothly
I have done my best
I don’t know if it’s perfect
But I have tried my best anyway
Then next
Is the story i want to tell tonight
I keep thinking about this story just like last week
I've been thinking about the question last week for a long time
But this week’s will be longer
There is one thing I can't understand
I can’t understand why in such a short story
Contains so much information
Especially the story of Cain and Abel
Whenever i read this story
I am always at a loss because
Because this story is only a short paragraph
Has no meaning
I think about it repeatedly
Whenever i think about it
I have a new understanding of this story
I can't understand why this happens
When I describe to you
The reasonable way is based on this point of view
That is, there is some wisdom in these stories
These wisdoms are generated from our interpersonal communication and behavior
Then show it on the image
They are in the long history
It is continuously condensed into clear text
And then for a long time
Repeated memory and transmission
Keep being refined
This is a good argument
I am happy to continue in this direction
But it keeps admiring me
There is so much information in such a short article
So we have to analyze it today
I think the story of Cain and Abel is especially true
Because it not only works at the individual level
It has also been confirmed at the family and political levels
Even at war
And economically applicable
It covers too much for one essential story
You may have to refute but such a story
You never know what you are reading
Don't know what this story means
This is part of the so-called "postmodern dilemma"
This question is reasonable
This question really can't find an answer like you can't
State exactly how you understand the world
Not completely correct but it is enough
One answer says
"Enough" means it is executable
Nobody else strongly disagrees you won't die because of it
And nature will not limit you
The limitations in our lives
You can be certain of your understanding to some extent
At least functionally feasible
This is very important
I guess you might want to explain these stories
Apply the same conditions
It may be good for now
But I hope you can be on multiple levels
Find functionally important explanations
But I think it might be very small
It’s like finding one at multiple levels at the same time
Applicable story interpretation
Then apply one more level
You stumbled upon a certain
The probability of accidental events will decrease, right?
There is a technical term in psychology
It seems to be called multiple traits and multiple methods
Is a way to define whether something is accurate
Its idea is
The more methods you use to get the same result
The more you can be sure that you are not
Use your prior assumptions to deceive yourself
But in fact it is
I guess this is another part of this method
This is also a method I used in my speech
I will not try to tell people any
Things that are not personal
Because you should know why you should teach you something
You should know what is good
It is personally good for you at least in a sense
And when you use it
It should be good for your family
Maybe it should be important in a wider social group
I think this is the so-called "meaning"
I don’t think the fact that being taught lacks meaning
is useful
Because the facts are infinite
And you can't remember them all
They must have substantial instrumental meaning
Because we are creatures that use tools
These stories happen to have these aspects
as far as I know
There is no doubt about this
These are the stories in the second chapter of "Genesis"
These stories are very famous
In fact, everyone is immersed in
Generally speaking, people in Western culture should have heard these stories
This is also a very interesting point
That the story can be so based
So that everyone has heard
You can also say
So are many fairy tales
Or until now you can at least assume so
But I think the foundation of the story
It also means that they must be given
Even if you don’t respect them, you will at least
Treat them as extraordinary curiosity
So why are these stories
Why are they passed down
Why everyone has heard
These questions cannot be answered with imagination
You can try to use Freud's explanation
Freud believed that Judaism and Christianity
Is based on the following viewpoints
The father in the family sense
Is extended to the dimension of the universe
And human beings have the same relationship with the Father of the universe
Just like the same baby or child
Relationship with father
I think this is a reasonable conclusion to some extent
But it does seem to Freud to be intentional
Does mean and not only
Belief that has at its apex
Anthropomorphic religious people
It's basically playing a role as a child under care
I have been thinking about this argument for a long time
Believe me this is a strong argument
In Ernest Becker’s "Death Denial"
This is one of the best books I have ever read
Just adopted the above argument
And like the others I’ve seen discussing this argument
The book has expanded
Becker tried to give Freud
Ending the psychoanalysis of religion
But he didn't do well
However, although I think this book is full of shortcomings and errors
But the flaws are not hiding
Some books are wrong but they are valuable
These books provide strong arguments
And take it to the extreme
But I think Becker ignored Jung’s point of view
It's as if Freud also ignored
Becker who wrote this book from the perspective of religious psychoanalysis
Never quote Jung’s views
Just mentioned in the introduction
I think this is the main mistake Becker made
But Becker adopted an argument
That is, the hypothesis about God is just a human attempt
Attempt to recreate an infant-like dependent state
To be able to rely on an omniscient priest
Maybe it’s to get back a comfortable feeling
This feeling is what we experienced when we were young
There is a father who seems to us to know everything
Or lucky enough
Have people who can bring similar feelings
The more I think about this, the more shocked I am
I always think it's impossible
I remember Charles Taylor
I wrote a book called
I remember it was called "The Urgency of the Modern Self"
He is a philosopher of McGill school
I would not say that he is a fan of classic religion
But it doesn't matter
Because he alone made a very interesting point about Christianity
He believes that if a religion is invented
It can only provide you with the comfort of infancy
Then why do you bother to imagine hell
This seems to be an unnecessary detail in the whole story
If religion is all about comfort
So why should people assume
The consequences of serious mistakes will be endless torture
It doesn't feel like
Something that makes you feel comfortable
When James Joyce wrote this
Talking about his very bad nightmares when he was a kid
It comes from the preaching process of the Jesuit priest
The raging fire in the hell mentioned
He also wrote down what he remembered
The content is creepy
In James Joyce's book
I remember it was called "A Portrait of a Young Artist"
The book talks about the Jesuit priest telling him
Hell is like a prison wall seven miles deep
Dark and dark
People locked there
Will always be burned by the flames in the dark
Above the flames, their bodies are constantly growing
Provide fuel for eternal hellfire
This is what everyone can't figure out
The reason why the fire of purgatory can never burn
This is the obvious process
I don’t think this shows the satisfaction of my childhood wishes
You may doubt it
Elaine Pagles who wrote a book about the devil
Is skeptical of this approach
She thinks it can be said to be a Christian
Invented hell as a place to place enemies
Ok this seems to make sense
But this is obviously inaccurate
Although there is a convenient place to put your enemies
For example, Charles Taylor clearly pointed out
The modern fear of losing yourself
Or the loss of self-existence and meaning
May be roughly similar to the fear of hell in the Middle Ages
In terms of existential strength
Hell is not only a
Where the people you don't care about end up
it's a
Where to go if you don't follow the rules
So I don’t think Freud’s view
Can stand up in the final analysis
Marx’s view is that religion is like the opium of the masses
He made a point similar to Freud
Just a little earlier
His view is based on the following assumptions
That is, religious belief is just a story for the vulnerable group
The purpose is to appease them
Such malicious exploiters
Can continue to exploit and weaken their power
I think "human institutions are
The view of "fully driven by power"
There is a problem to say the least
Of course every human organization will
Corrupt for various reasons
Also because it's especially like cheating
Corrupt by arrogantly coveting power
The religious system is not exempt
But this does not mean
They can be on these defects
Show some distinctive characteristics
Maybe you think they can
Maybe you can find a convincing reason for it
But you can’t say that this is generally obvious from preliminary proof
Treat it as a particularly useful criticism
I can't agree
I think people who hold this view are too suspicious
I think for the people who write these stories
First of all, what do you plan to do
You guys want to successfully plan one
A stunning conspiracy that lasted 3000 years?
Good luck then
You can't even plan a plot that lasts a quarter of an hour
Without being cast aside by everyone
This is impossible
No matter what the foundation of the architecture is
Not only the basis of these stories
And the dogmatic structure that emerged on this basis
I think only a single dimension of explanation is used to summarize them
Really wrong
In fact I always think
Any behavior that reduces complex human performance to a single dimension
Are only done by single-minded thinkers
I said this after careful consideration
Because Freud treated religion the same way
At least to some extent
Freud is a rigorous thinker
I think Marx is also a rigorous thinker
Even though he
Ok
He is a
As long as you have a sense of reason
You will be dumbfounded at Marx
Anyway what I want to say is I don’t think
Can any simple explanation
Can explain why these stories are so powerful
I don’t think you can reduce it to a political conspiracy
There is no doubt about this
I don’t think you can reduce it to mental naivety
I think you can think of them like me
A treasure trove of human collective wisdom
I received an interesting letter this week
I have many interesting letters
I think I can put them in order
And put it on the website some time
Of course you have to get their permission
The letter said he has been listening to my lectures
And noticed that I was looking for a
What can be called quasi-organism or evolutionary reason
Used to study the generation of information contained in the story
He also said, "How do you know people of different religions
"Or people with different religious traditions
"Won't do exactly the same thing"
I think first
It is possible to some extent
Because their religions overlap
For example, some things I talked about about Taoism
Taoism treats being as
Balance between eternal chaos and order
One thing I didn’t mention I didn’t think about
I don't know if you know
There is a neuropsychologist named Eknane Goldberg
He is a student of Alexander Lulia
I think Lulia
Is the greatest neuropsychologist of the 20th century
He is russian
He was the first group to be truly sure in general
One of the functional people of the prefrontal cortex
Its function has been a mystery for a long time
Speaking of Goldberg, everyone knows that the human brain has two hemispheres
Left brain and right brain
People usually think that the left brain is for right-handed people
Especially right-handed men
Because women's neurological functions are more scattered
This makes women more able to withstand brain damage
Maybe the male brain function is more concentrated
This makes the male brain function more specialized
But more vulnerable
Closer to home, the human brain has two hemispheres left and right
But no one knows why
We know that the left and right brains each have a similar consciousness
If you separate the corpus callosum connecting the left and right brains
For example, to treat certain cases of intractable epilepsy
Every hemisphere can to some extent
Develop their own consciousness independently
The right brain is usually nonverbal while the left brain is verbal
So there is a view that the left brain is a language hemisphere
The right brain is a nonverbal hemisphere
But this is not right because obviously animals can’t speak
But animals also have separate brain hemispheres
So even if it is true
Causally has nothing to do with language
Goldberg proposed another hypothesis
That is, the left and right brains are respectively specialized in routine and unconventional activities
Or rather novel and familiar with chaos and order
This is really a bold idea
When i first heard this
I also treat it as a signal
A so-called
The verification signal of the structure of the multiple characteristics and multiple methods
Because i never thought about it
The brain hemisphere will behave in this way
And Goldberg put forward this point in the course of history
This view and any thinking inspired by myth
All completely different
Lack of relevance
In fact it is more subject to materialism
The advancement of Russian neuropsychology
The subject is classified as materialism for political reasons
There are also scientific reasons
But the core point is that one hemisphere of the human brain
Can react quickly to things we are not familiar with
This hemisphere is more imaginative and more distributed
And it’s more related to negative emotions
Because negative emotions can be perceived immediately
When you encounter something you don’t understand
Negative emotions are actually a way of thinking
I'm in a state of not knowing how things are going
The right brain will remind you
Then the right brain will quickly generate video
To help you figure out what's in front of you
Then the left brain takes over
Use this thing more clearly
The rigorous explanation allows you to fully understand
So there is a dynamic balance between the left and right hemispheres
The left brain tries to establish the order of the world
Ramachandran
A very famous neuroscientist in California
Also developed a theory similar to Goldberg
He believes that the left brain has established a regular order of the world
The right brain is responsible for creating novelty
React to new things and generate novel hypotheses
He believes that with the support of existing good evidence
What happens in my sleep is exactly
Right brain to left brain
Little by little transmission of information
Such a novel revelation for the right brain
So as not to damage the left brain carefully built
Rigorous structural order
I also like this theory
Because it also helps to prove
The hypothesis I have been expounding for you
That is, a part of our individual extends self to the whole world
And trying to understand things we don’t understand
That part extends itself to behavior
Emotions and video
Possibly also poetry and narrative
With the development process
We have developed more and more
Clear expression of emerging knowledge
So you can map it to neurologists in a good place
About the neuropsychologist
What constitutes the presumption of brain hemisphere differentiation
One more cool thing
Demonstration about the differentiation of brain hemispheres
As far as I know, it’s worth thinking about
Because it's too
Ned Flanders used one word to describe
"Staggering"
I think it probably means this haha
Anyway we do assume
We are biologically adapted to reality
If you are a darwinist
This is actually an axiomatic definition
Because by definition natural selection
This is the natural survival of the fittest
If natural selection of species with separate brain hemispheres
Because half of you need to deal with chaos
The other half of you need to maintain order
So you can draw conclusions that can stand scrutiny
The world is born out of chaos and order
This is something worth thinking about
if you are willing to
You can take some time to think about it
To blame for some reason
These stories cover a lot of content
We continue to study some
Let’s start with the story of Adam and Eve
You may remember that the Bible is a series of books
The Bible is actually like a library
These books are written by different people
Edited by different people
Edited countless times in the long river of history
Not by someone alone, but by a hundred schools of thought
For a long time there was a default tradition that
The first book that appeared was written by Moses
To be honest, this may be incorrect
Although it may be correct from a dramatic point of view
Or it is "fairy-tale correctness"
I don't mean to belittle fairy tales
These authors
For now, the way to identify these authors is
Identify certain stylistic characteristics in different stories
Use of words
Such as the term "God"
Different poetry styles, different themes, etc.
People spent almost 200 years
Trying to figure out who wrote which article
How did these stories piece together
This is not important for our purposes
The important thing is that it is a collection of collective narrative traditions
Or a collection of collective narrative wisdom
We can not discuss it so deeply
But at least we can say that it is a collection of narrative traditions
These traditions are kept and others are abandoned
There is a reason
The stories are arranged in a specific order
There are also complicated reasons
The Bible as literature
The very good point is
It’s really plot-like.
It involves many levels
But it has been in thousands of years
Pieced together by people
Maybe 4000 years maybe longer
If you count the previous oral tradition period
God knows how long
Part of human collective imagination
Put together a library with a storyline
I see the Bible as
A collective attempt by mankind to solve the most profound problems
I think these are questions about self-awareness
About us are not immortal
The fact that we are going to die and know it well
This is a unique dilemma for mankind
Distinguish us from everything
This is shown in the story of Adam and Eve
I think what makes us so unique
Shown in the story of Adam and Eve
Interestingly
I realize this is
After finishing the previous three lectures
The Bible describes the great changes at the beginning of time
This great change has given mankind a sense of self
Cracks in the structure of existence
This is the correct way to understand
This has cosmic significance
You can refute
Events that happen to humans
Won't have cosmic meaning
We are just a fleeting dog-like entity
Living here like a cancer
Sojourn in the vast sky
In the corner of an unknown galaxy
Rotating on a little planet
Everything that happens to us is meaningless
You can stick to this point of view
I would not recommend you to do this
Part of the reason is
This is untrue for whatever purpose
You can't live well with such thoughts
In fact, if you really insist on this idea
If you really think so
You may lose your life in the end
This really reminds me
I have talked to many people with serious suicidal tendencies
Before they give birth to the idea of ​​ending their lives
Their conclusions about the utility of life
And you stick to the conclusion of that idea
Are highly similar
If you are interested
You can read Leo Tolstoy's "Confessions"
This is a short and powerful book
Tolstoy described his time in the heyday of fame
Desire for suicide
The most famous author in the world
High-ranking households are world-renowned
We are admired by thousands of people
He has everything you can imagine
He didn't dare to walk into the barn with a rope or gun
He was afraid he would hang himself or shoot himself
He finally came out of the shadows
And what he experienced
This is a very good book
The "Bible" story beginning with Adam and Eve
Tells a different story
They bring the emergence of human self-consciousness
Considered as a cosmic change event
You might ask
What do we have to do with the universe
the answer is
Depends on what you think is the relationship between consciousness and the universe
Maybe it has nothing to do
I will choose closely related
Because in my opinion
Of course you can disagree
But if you think
Consciousness is a force with universal meaning
Being itself depends on any real meaning
At least on any empirical meaning
Then the following assumptions are reasonable
That is, the complete reconstruction of consciousness can be given
Some kind of cosmic or metaphysical meaning
Even from a perspective other than human
It is still incorrect
Whatever it means
It is real from a human perspective
It's certain
In a sense this is the first event since the creation of the world
Catastrophic fall
The rest of the Bible
Are trying to figure out how to deal with it
For example, in the Old Testament story
What happened next was the establishment of the State of Israel
Then rise and fall
Then people started
Hundreds or even thousands of years of exploration
Follow this point of view
In the tragic result of self-consciousness
Ways to protect yourself
Is dedicated to the country
But it turned out that the country itself began to show morbidity
When these illnesses start to accumulate
The country began to fall apart
Then rise again and rebirth
It collapses and rebirth repeatedly
So many cycles
This mainly comes from the explanation of Northrop Frye
People began to think "the country is the place of salvation"
Is this idea wrong?
Is this idea flawed?
On this basis
There was a Christian revolution
And such a hypothesis
"The country is not a place of salvation"
The individual's mind is
And correspondingly appeared the ethical system
It's also very interesting
The ethics of salvation after the failure of the “state experiment” is
"Salvation is presented in the mind of the individual"
Even in terms of country
Because of the normal operation of the country
Depends on the normal operation of the individual
Fundamentally and not the other way around
The correct way to redeem individuals is truth
The truth is in the story of Adam and Eve
The antidote to the suffering caused by the fall of man
This echoes the chapter we discussed earlier
There is a claim in the first chapter of Genesis
Is the way of truth to create order in chaos
But more importantly
This is also when I gave the lecture three weeks before
Just realized
When God uses truth to introduce order into existence
He kept saying
The being that he introduced into being is good
Have such a proposition
Beings that introduce beings through truth are good
The interesting thing is at the beginning of the story
Have such a hint
It’s about the state of being enshrined in Adam and Eve
Before they fell and gained self-awareness
They were created in the image of God
And revealed the following truths
That is, "the existence itself is reasonably balanced"
The entire Bible is a re-exploration of this view
This is a trace to the origin
This is a classic mythological theme
Wise people are
The person who regained what was lost in childhood
I think this is a Jewish concept
If I remember correctly
Is a messianic character
Is the one who regained what was lost in childhood
There is back to the original concept
But you are not falling back to childhood and unconsciousness
But you return to your childhood fully awake and spontaneously
Then decided to pass the truth
To participate in the presentation of reasonable beings
I study psychology
I have been teaching personality theory for a long time
I have a deep understanding of personality theory
I also know something about philosophy
Although I don’t know enough
But what i can tell you is
In all the theories that I have read and encountered
I have never seen any theory so profound
Not only profound but also credible
As a clinician, I also observed
I think this is unique to clinical experience
And was accurately described by outstanding clinicians
"It is the truth that can heal the pain in treatment."
The truth is the cure
There are clinical exposure treatments for what you fear
There are also escape treatments
But I think this is a form of practicing the truth
If you know what you need to do according to your own standards
But avoid doing it
Then you are practicing lies
You did not verbally lie
You are practicing lies with actions
No different at all
So if I can let you face
Things you know you shouldn't avoid
We are all involved
The process of trying to make you show the deepest truth
This can improve people's lives
Can completely improve their lives
Numerous clinical evidence
We know if you expose people to
They are afraid and in front of things they avoid
They can overcome it slowly
You have to be careful
Involve them in the process
But there is one point in all the theories established by clinicians
This is first of all credible
Based on deeper consciousness
That is, clinical experience is redeemable
It aims to solve the pain
Because the people involved in this process
Are telling the truth
You will think this is obvious
Because when you have a problem and come to talk to me
First when you come to talk to me
You acknowledged the problem
This is a good start
Second, if you talk to me
We know the problem
If we know the problem
We can start to list some solutions
Then you can put it into practice to see if these methods are effective
But if you don’t admit the problem
Refused to tell me what the problem was
And I'm pretending to be mysterious
Always dominate the conversation
What's the use
We are immersed in delusion
Maybe this will bring short-term comfort
But it is useless
If you think about it, it's obvious
Freud believed that depression is the core of mental pain
Repression and deception are only the difference in degree
Nothing more
Is the difference in degree
Alfred Adler
Is one of Freud’s best colleagues
I think he is underestimated
He thinks people are in trouble
Because of practicing the "life lie"
He put forward the "life lie"
This is worth studying
Because Adler is not as attractive as Freud
But he is very practical
He did foresee the development of cybernetics
Jung thinks you can
Only by making appropriate moral efforts in life
You can ignore psychotherapy completely
Carl Rogers thinks
Candid communication through dialogue
Can produce salvation results
Behaviouralists believe that micro-analysis of the problems before them
And then lead people to face the things they avoid
All of this seems to me just
The secular variant of "the truth will set you free"
This is a very powerful story
First of all, this story is not easy to ignore
Secondly, if you ignore it, you are actually taking a risk
I have seen people who have been deeply hurt
Mostly hurt by deception
This is worth thinking about
Life will hit you head on
There is no doubt about this
But I thought for a long time
People can withstand earthquakes, cancer and even death
But they can't bear betrayal and can't bear cheating
They can't bear someone trusted by the one they love
Deception and betrayal
This will destroy them
It makes them sick and painful
Cause psychological and physical trauma
Not only that
Betrayal will make them
Cynical, bitter, vicious and resentful
They also started to do evil to the world, forming a vicious circle
At the beginning of the story
God uses truth to create good beings
Then the disaster happened
Mankind spent thousands of years
Trying to figure out how to deal with this catastrophe
The fact that they have self-awareness
We are indeed self-conscious
Other animals have no such consciousness
You will read about chimpanzees as an example
If you put lipstick on chimps
This is a strange thing
I don't want to repeat it
If you show chimps in the mirror
It will wipe off the lipstick
Dolphins seem to be able to distinguish themselves in the mirror
There is a budding of self-consciousness in other animals
But put it in the concept of human self-consciousness
I think
At least it is not yet formed
But I also think it is caused by
Driven by a potential anti-humanist drive
Human self-awareness has developed very well
The self-awareness of animals is totally different
It’s like when the vervet monkey spotted the predator
Warning call
Compared with human language
There are indeed similarities between the two
Animal calls are also meaningful
But the call is not language
The self-consciousness of animals is the original self-consciousness
There are few self-aware animals
Incomparable with humans
They have no idea of ​​the future
They don’t know their limitations in time and space
this is very important
Especially time
Humans "discovered" time
When we "discovered" time
We have discovered the end of each of our beings
This distinguishes us from animals
This is the connotation of the story of Adam and Eve
The first chapter of "Genesis" is from the priest's literature
God is called in priest literature
"Ilohim" or "Ilshade"
There are singular gods and plural gods
I think the reason is
If you analyze the history of monotheism
Monotheism actually developed from polytheism
As i said before
I think the gods represent the fundamental power
These fundamental forces must be organized in hierarchy
Must have authority
Otherwise they can only conflict with each other and achieve nothing
Value must be organized in levels
Or just one
Whether it's for the individual
Still for the country
If you don’t know what to do next
You do it all blindly
This is doomed to nothing
You have to sort out the priority
One thing always takes precedence over others
Arrange according to the hierarchy to avoid chaos
So the rules of hierarchy appeared in the gods
Maybe there is still a long run-in
The battle of the gods described by Mircea Iliad
If interested
You can read "History of Religious Thought"
I recommend you to read
This book has three volumes
Relatively easy to understand
For religious books
Eliade developed polytheism to monotheism
The process and reasons are explained clearly
Even in polytheism
The gods are also very inclined to build their own hierarchy
And promoted a supreme god in power
In a sense
Except for the most powerful god
The other gods are gone with time
But even in the polytheistic essay
There is also a hierarchy of power among the gods
The first chapter of "Genesis" is newer than the second chapter
The story I want to parse today
Longer than the one I said before
Although their order was reversed by the editor
This editor is hypothetical
Maybe a group of editors
They collected these stories
I think it’s unlikely that there is only one person who knows
We still don’t know why these stories
Are arranged in this order
But we can infer this arrangement order
Is a reasonable order considered by the editor
This is the editor’s job
Edited different ideas
Arrange in a reasonable order
Reasonable order means
You can tell people these thoughts
Keep them interested
And let them remember these points
This is also one of the reasonable standards for determining your argument
Because your argument is communicable, understandable and memorable
We can say it is driven by intuition
This person arranges these stories in this order
The Jehovah Document contains
The classic story of the Torah
"Genesis" "Exodus" "Leviticus"
"Numbers" "Deuteronomy"
I hope that in these 12 lectures we can all talk about
Let's watch while walking
There are many personifications in the Jehovah literature
So the God in Jehovah’s documents
In a sense, it’s a "yuan man"
I read a little bit last week
People tend to think this is imperfect
But you think so
Mind is the foundation of consciousness
Is the most complicated thing we know
Then imagine this most complicated thing like this
Not so perfect
At least this is people's exhaustion of imagination
The best result you can get
So i don't think it is imperfect
It can be inferred from this
Very practically
The following ideas are also very reasonable
That the Father is from
The spirit that rises from the crowd and continues into the future
When we discuss the concept of sacrifice
Involved some
Or we will talk about this later
You will sacrifice the present
Let yourself be more satisfied in the future
But the problem is
What kind of future will satisfy you
The answer is the spirit of all mankind
This is what you negotiate
You can make an assumption
If you sacrifice willful play
Go all out to get a medical degree
Ten years later when you become a doctor
Human society will respect your dedication and commitment
And open the door to you
You not only treat the future as an independent being
Treat it as a compassionate judge
You are putting it into practice
Maybe before we start to understand that there is a future
You have to imagine God as an ununderstood form
Maybe think of God as such a form
We can make things concrete and deal with them
We can learn how to use sacrifice
To understand how to guide us into the future
Sacrifice is a contract with the future
Not a contract with a specific person
Is a contract with all mankind
When you think in this way
It will give you an initiation
Because this is a great idea
Allows you to bargain with the future
This idea is amazing
It’s the most important idea for us as human beings
What to do if we suffer
We have to figure out how to discuss with the future
And use this method to minimize our suffering
No other animal can do it
The lion only has what to eat
A wolf can eat 40 pounds of meat
Eat as long as there is meat
I won’t say save some mammoth for tomorrow.
Wolves won’t do this, but humans will
That means you may be starving today
Imagine you are a farmer 6000 years ago
At the beginning of the farming civilization, you were about to starve to death
Looking forward to spring ploughing
You know you better not touch those seeds
This ability is very important to control the present self
Let the future come true
And postpone what you can enjoy now
Instead of using it on impulse
Maybe your child is starving to death
You still can’t touch the seeds you will use in the future
For mankind to realize that there is a future
And the ability to plan for the future
This is too important i think
In fact, at least part of the story in the book is
Describes the birth process of this ability
Jehovah's documentation begins in chapter 2 section 4 of Genesis
"This is how the world was created" (Genesis 2:4)
There are two true creation stories at the beginning
The later one is the first one
The longer one is the second
The Jiuyuan Edition starts with Chapter 2 of Genesis
Which is what we are going to talk about next
Including Adam and Eve, Cain and Abel
Noah Babel
Chapters in Jehovah's Documents
"Exodus" "Numbers"
There are also some priest documents
The Ten Commandments are also included
There are many vivid descriptions of heaven
This is "The Paradise on Earth"
I forgot what the author was called
Boss
To Jeronimos Boss
A madman
I can't understand why he was not burned to death on the stake
Most of you know Salvador Dali
He is insignificant compared to Boss
You might spend a whole month
Observe this painting with a weird and outrageous feeling
I don't know what happened to Boss
But he is the kind of creature that only appears once in history
This may be a good thing
There have always been many expressions about heaven
God knows what heaven means in this painting
I can only guess at best but I won’t do that
There is a lion lying among the sheep
Here is such a concept
Reflects the past
Or maybe at some point in the future
Fear of survival
There is no need for life itself
And the scary thing about life is of course
It's the eclipse of everything
All things perish and all things are reborn
The whole land is a morgue
Full of disasters from beginning to end
This fantasy is the exact opposite of the previous one
Have a very deep thought
This idea is also implicit in one of the alchemy ideas
I think it is also one of the ideas implicit in the scientific revolution
Interact with reality with this thought
Humans can reduce tragedy and depravity
To be able to
This is obviously imagist
Maybe we can get closer to the place transformed by this thought
Where we enjoy the benefits of actual existence
Without any disaster
When Jung wrote that science begins with alchemy
He believes that science is driven by dreams
For Jung, dream is the embodiment of instinct
It exists at the boundary between instinct and mind
Science is embedded in dreams
Dream is some kind
If we are fully focused and sincere
To observe the structure of physical reality
Can understand material reality and reduce suffering
Stone of the Sage
Make everyone rich and make everyone healthy
Something that makes everyone immortal
This is the ultimate goal to alleviate existing disasters
Solutions to the mystery of life
May let us find such a theme
Or put it this way
To provide the driving force for the development of science
Jung put the power of development
Going back more than 1,000 years ago
If you are interested in reading his book about alchemy
Those books are extremely difficult to understand
It also confirms the profound knowledge of Jung
Because his books are hard to read
It can be said that books on alchemy have taken a quantum leap
That seems to be a "small" leap
I shouldn't say that
It should be said that these books have taken a big step
Stepped into a completely different complex latitude
But this is also the latitude Jung tried to step into
He reinterpreted alchemy literature
As if they are dreams established by science
By the way, Newton was also an alchemist
The hypothesis put forward by Jung is well confirmed by history
The birth of science really began with alchemy
The question is what does alchemy do
They try to refine the sage stone
This is also the panacea pursued by human pathology
Jung felt that what happened was
Christianity promised to stop suffering
Said it for more than 1,000 years
The pain has not been abated yet
Simultaneously
Christianity tried to really value spiritual construction
For example, at the expense of material development
Treat it as something similar to sin
Try to restrain impulse
All of these are accompanied by the existence of a twin
There is a reason
European minds around 1000 AD
Got some education
And be able to focus on a single point
Maybe because of long and intensive religious training
Pull down religious dreams from the unexplored material world
Europeans think about it then
The spiritual salvation we have been pursuing
Does not seem to make promises and expected results
Achieved
Maybe we should seek answers in another place
And the answer lies in the cursed world of material desire
that place
At least based on the traditional perspective
Just a place to create demons
What i want to say is
People have many motivations, it’s hard to underestimate their number
These motives are deeply rooted in people's attempts to relieve pain
People try to eradicate the disease
Help others lead a healthy life
Reduce disease health and longevity
Do things in a peaceful manner as much as possible
You can say that the world does not speak morality, justice and self-interest
You can also say that they are all driven by power
Corruption
All these things are right
But you shouldn’t totally deny human beings for this flaw
Because we worked hard for a long time to get things right
What we have achieved today is already very good
For our half-hungry state of madness
Insect-ridden
And for chimpanzees with a life span of only 50 to 70 years
For the status of human beings today
We deserve a little sympathy
What you want me to say
Some other explanations about heaven
I like this picture
This one on the left
Heaven is a garden in a trap
The meaning of heaven is the same
From the word "parádeisos" it is
Don't remember what language it is
Anyway related to Persian
"Parádeisos" means garden
Why is it a garden?
We have to go back to the concept of chaos and order
After creation
God put men and women in the garden
Entrapment means culture and order, garden means nature
Illustrates a place suitable for human habitation
Is a place where nature and civilization strike a balance
We like the garden why
Because the garden is not completely covered by weeds and mosquitoes
Covered by flies, right
So the garden is more or less civilized
But in this civilization
Nature thrives with a more kind and benevolent attitude
People think this idea is full of life
I feel "Heaven, a livable place for humans
"It's a garden" This idea is good
There is a wall because you want to block something out
For example raccoon
You want to keep it out even if it’s impossible
There must be various things
You don’t want them to appear in the garden like snakes
If you want to come in, the wall doesn't seem to be able to stop
But the idea that "heaven is a garden"
Echoes the concept of chaos and order at the beginning
The wall is the civilized garden is the nature
The ideal human habitat is like a well-tended garden
Radical leftist anti-theist environmentalist
Tend to prove
The plunder of Western capitalism is actually
The consequences of humans following an instruction
In "Genesis", God gave mankind
The command is to go out and dominate the world
David Suzuki also talked a lot about it
They believe this statement makes
We wished
The right to control the world
This statement turned humans into terrible carnivorous monsters
Sometimes humans are described as tumors on the surface of the earth
Or viruses that parasitize the entire ecosystem
Not only did not build on the earth, but also wandered around all day
Mess everywhere
This is another perspective on human nature
But I think it must be strongly condemned
If you look at the history
You will find
By the end of the 19th century Thomas Huxley
Grandpa of Aldous Huxley
Darwin's big supporter
Wrote a report to the British government for the sustainability of the ocean
The conclusion he gave is to fish as much as you like
There are thousands of fish in the ocean
The resources of the ocean are inexhaustible
No matter how many years humans try their best to take
Have an impact on marine ecology
The possibility can only be zero
Now things prove Huxley wrong
He didn't expect that the population would surge like a magic
Part of the reason is that we have become richer
The newborn will never be like before
The infant mortality rate is as high as 60% before reaching their first birthday
Even if only a few people
We can thrive
We only realized in the 1960s
We have too much population
Must start paying attention
What we do to the earth
This is 50 years ago
We just started to develop technology
And the necessary technology
To understand that the whole world should be considered a garden
We have to find the balance between civilization and chaos inside
before this
We just tried our best to survive
And usually fail
So I don’t agree with this interpretation of the beginning of "Genesis"
I do not believe
Human beings are empowered on this planet
To act as a super predator
On the contrary I think
Compare the garden to a suitable habitat for humans
Is quite appropriate
People's role
It is also clearly stated in the second story
Adam and Eve are looking after the garden
Illustrate the appropriate choice
Let everything thrive and thrive
Not only good for other creatures
Good for humans too
I think now we at least
Can notice what is commonly proposed today
Compared to the final cynical interpretation of this story
This is just a slightly different angle of interpretation of the story
There are several trees in the garden
There are Adam and Eve, some animals and so on
Unfortunately this tree happened to be entangled by a snake
This is interesting
Next we will have a lot of discussion about this
Snakes are unusual in both pictures
It has a human head
The one in the other picture also has a human head
No matter what kind of snake it is
Don’t look at it from a religious perspective
If you can't do it, imagine you are a anthropologist
You have never seen this painting
What do you see at this moment
You see the wall and a very comfortable enclosed space
Then you see a tree
People are eating from the tree
There is a snake with a human head on the tree
You might wonder why this snake has a human head
Then you will think
This is half snake and half human
This hardly reveals anything
It speaks for itself
So no matter what it is
Anyway, it's not just a snake
It is a snake and a human
Or a snake but some of the characteristics of a human
This is very important we will analyze next
Here you see the same thing
In this picture you can see
There is a head there
This snake has two wings
This is a snake with wings a bit like a dragon
Can crawl on the ground like a reptile
It has a flying animal side or a spiritual side
This snake is like the lowest form of reptile life
Is something crawling on the ground
It's a human body and a spirit body
It perches on this tree
This tree looks a lot like hallucinogenic mushrooms by the way
If you want to know, you can check
This theme is also unique
If you are curious about it
But there is another thought here
That is, there was such a thing in the garden at the beginning of time
This thing is like a snake and a person
This thing has wings and spirituality
So it is a combination of spiritual humans and reptiles
It is also the vivid spirit of this tree
Well remember this
"Heaven and earth are made" (Genesis 2:1)
This is related to the first chapter of "Genesis"
"All things are made together" (Genesis 2:1)
"By the seventh day
"Just stopped all his work on the seventh day
"Rest in peace
"God bless the seventh day
"Sacred Day
"Because on this day God stopped all the work of creation
"Rest in peace" (Gen 2:3)
The concept of the Sabbath is wisdom
I have worked with a lot of people who work too hard
The problem with overly serious people is
They will work till they die
This actually does not make them highly efficient
Because they can't work if they die
What you have to do to them is you have to tell them
I know you don't want to do anything except work
Maybe when you are not working
You will sink into guilt
But first figure out what you are doing
What you are doing is doing everything possible
Try with least doubt
Use the longest sustainable time
Possible ways to work efficiently
That may mean you need to rest
I used to work with lawyers
They have risen to the top of a large law firm
Are the kind of people who work super efficiently
They often try to challenge
Their impossible annual working hour quota
In the end, I made myself burnt
One of our actions for this situation is
It won’t work for them to reduce the number of working days
But we will let them extend their rest time
For example, take a four-day weekend every two months
Help them plan their work and rest schedule
We will track and study their charging time
Because this is their productivity
The result is that their charging time has really improved
This is great because you can tell workaholics
Rest
why
Because it will make your work more efficient
No this is impossible
I should always try my best to work
Then test it
You take a break every now and then
As a result, their work efficiency has increased
Usually 10%
So resting is also a kind of wisdom
This is the end of Chapter One
Foreshadowing the story of Adam and Eve
You have self-awareness, you explore the future
You have to work
The question is how much do you have to work
One answer is
You better work hard all the time
Because no matter how much you work
You can't solve your problem
Problems will always come
You can save a bunch of money you want
You can save a bunch of whatever you want
But in the end none of these things can protect you
So you'd better keep your feet on the ground and work hard
It's best to do your best all the time
What will happen if you do
You will die
That's not a good solution
So maybe you should rest
How to put rest into practice
It's hard to say but there is a way
Let's talk about it conceptually
Even God has to take one day off every week
So you don’t have to assume that
If God had to take one day off every week
Then you have to work non-stop
I think our culture has been in a rather dangerous way
Embarked on this astray
Every place is open all day long
But like you guys, I also find it very convenient
It’s weird to talk to modern people
The one thing they tell you most is
We asked "how are you"
What do they often say
They don’t say “good” or “bad”
They will say "busy"
Speechless
Well, the second chapter of "Genesis" starts here
Finally here
"The origin of the creation of heaven and earth
"On the day when the Lord God made the heavens and the earth
"That's it" (Genesis 2:4)
"There is no vegetation in the wild
"The vegetables in the field haven't grown
"Because the Lord God has not rained on the earth
"No one cultivates the land" (Gen 2:5)
"But there is mist rising from the ground
"Moisturizes everywhere" (Gen 2:6)
"The Lord God used the dust of the earth to create man
"Blow anger into his nostrils
"He became a living being with spirit" (Gen 2:7)
There is a very old idea here
Breath is life
Breath of inspiration
They are all connected
It's vitality like the air in the tires
Is breathing
The reason why people associate life with breath
Not so stupid
You are breathing this is what you are doing all the time
When you die, breathing will stop
Breath is an integral part of life
This perfectly reasonable speculation happens to be very true
The act of creating inspiration
Connected
Inject the breath of life into something inanimate
What can you expect from this sentence
It behaves well enough
"The Lord God established a garden in Eden in the east" (Gen 2:8)
Eden is a place with plenty of water
This is especially meaningful
If you are a resident of the desert
The problem you are facing is
"Is there enough water for you to grow things"
This garden is the Paradise of Eden
Where there is sufficient water
Water has the characteristics of chaos
We learned early in the first chapter of "Genesis"
The underlying chaos is usually considered similar to water
Is a symbol of water
The same idea
A certain amount of chaos must transform it into order
So that chaos can become fruitful
You know that all the fruits are nourished by water
"The Lord God made all kinds of trees grow out of the ground
"It's pleasing to the eyes
"The fruit on it is good for food
"There is another tree of life in the garden
"The tree of separation of good and evil" (Gen 2:9)
So these two trees are divided
Among them is the tree of life
And the tree of good and evil
When you are reading this kind of stuff, if you think
You enter the category of metaphor
We have to be cautious about metaphors
Because i can say
I did say
The idea of ​​chaos and order is a metaphor
I also said to think carefully
Although this is a metaphor
But this is also a way of thinking that your brain adapts to
Let's stop playing tricks in this way of thinking
It's just a metaphor and nothing more
The same thing happened here
These are metaphors
The tree of life can distinguish good from evil
They are not just metaphors
Sometimes like I said before
If you are in a series of things
Use abstract thinking to propose a common factor
You can have enough confidence to say
The ratio of common factors extracted by abstraction
This series of things is more real
This is the practicality of abstraction
Otherwise, why would you bother about it?
If you can't list these things
Cite this series of things
Commonality more important than differences
Then you don’t need abstract ability
The tree of life and the tree that distinguishes good from evil
Is the result of abstraction
Now there is a problem
Hard question
I thought about it for a long time
Why a fruit or something you eat
Can be related to psychological changes
It happened in the story of Adam and Eve
Why something you eat
Student of Eric Newman Jung
Have studied this on this
He gave a more appropriate explanation
He said we always know the act of eating
Especially when you are hungry or need food urgently
Can produce a quick mental change
This is worth noting some of you
Probably have had a grumpy partner or child
Everyone has experienced
When their temperament becomes erratic
Inexplicably cloudy and sunny
You just give them some food
Really I tell you it works very well
I often do this to my patients
They told me
They will get furious about a little bit of something
Well, let me say try this method for a week
When your temper becomes unreasonable
Eat a small cheese or peanut butter sandwich
Eat some high-protein and high-fat foods
Then wait ten minutes to see if you are normal
You will find that sanity comes back after eating
You can't believe it
How crazy people would be when hungry
This is amazing
Try if you skip breakfast
Your life will change
Here are some useful information
For those who are dissatisfied with society and ended up in prison
If you are in jail you want to get parole
You have to go to the judge
Tell him why you won't do it again
Here is a trick
What you have done is not that important
The promise you made is not important
The important thing is
Did you see the judge before he had lunch or after lunch
If it was after the judge had lunch,
Your chances of getting parole will increase by 60%
Yes that's it
So never when you are hungry
Argue with your partner
Or when they are hungry
Especially when you want something from them
Best to come here and have a sandwich
They will eat it and you are at your disposal
Don't think about it before they eat
So this idea is not unreasonable
There is a certain spirit in the food that can make you refreshed
Not only to refresh your body
Mentally too
Of course, other things can also achieve this effect
But they are not like food
Has a great influence on our spirit
Take alcohol for example
Dionysus
He is Bacchus
Bacchus takes over your body
And let you do all kinds of funny things that alcohol brings you
An act that will make you regret it when you wake up the next day
So it has such a spiritual element
But going deeper
It connects food and information, which is great
The story of Adam and Eve shows
Fruits make psychological changes
So the tree of good and evil
Is an abstract summary of all trees
It tries to tell you that there are commonalities between trees and trees
Fruit is the commonality of trees
Probably like that
You might call this commonality food
Although it's only a rough generalization, it doesn't lose sense
What’s cooler is in the whole food field
The most stable element is not food
But the information it contains
We use the same brain circuit to search for information
The brain circuit of squirrel searching for food is the same
It’s the same brain circuit as animals searching for food
Why is it the same
Because we understand
Knowing where to have food is more important than having food
Knowing where the food is the primary form of food
Information is meta food
This is why we are the collectors of information
Once you catch this point
This idea is rooted in the story of Adam and Eve
No matter what the food form inside
What they eat is meta food
Some kind of information
We will exchange information with food, right
Imagine you are trapped by the highway
You open the hood
Found your car turned into a pile of scrap iron
You have no idea about it
Suddenly someone stopped next to you
They are mechanics
They pointed to a device and said
You just put that wire back there
You will give him a sandwich right away, right
Or something else in return
You know what I mean because they provide you
Valuable information
Information is valuable because it gives you motivation
Information can power you
Otherwise, why would we bother about it?
So it’s the same with food providing power information
Food philosophy
That you can get from all the things you can eat
Furthermore, you can get from all sources of food
What is abstracted out is information
The tree in the story of Adam and Eve is the meta form of the tree
Not the normality of the tree
It’s like heaven is not a specific ordinary place
Just like Adam and Eve are not ordinary people
Like the logos used by God at the beginning of time
Not just concepts
They are not just metaphors
Something deeper than metaphor
I think this is surreal
They are more real than what you see
More real than what you see
Many things are like this
The numbers are like this
Just because there is something more real than seeing
Then you will think and do abstract refinement
So what is the real thing
This is also part of what we want to understand
"The Lord God made all kinds of trees grow out of the ground
"It's pleasing to the eyes
"The fruit on it is good for food
"There is another tree of life in the garden
"The Tree of Separation of Good and Evil" (Genesis 2:9)
"A river flows from Eden to nourish the garden
"Divided into four paths from there" (Gen 2:10)
There are a lot of conjectures here
Eden is also a holy city
This is another way of looking at it
Or Jerusalem
Or an ideal country may also be an ideal city
It may also be the ideal state of being
Or ideal mind
It's all of them superimposed together
This is an imaginary mandala form
Make up the structure of heaven
You will notice that it has this cross pattern
This is the Garden of Eden itself
This is the center of the Garden of Eden, this is the river
Those on the left are rivers, not snakes
Those are the rivers that flow from the garden
And they were transformed into representatives that Jung described as me
These mandala images
Will be the core element of the conscious being
Jung combined it with divinity
And the concept of holy city
I show you this
To present the concept of imaginary heaven
"The first one is named Bisson
"It surrounds the whole land of Havilah
"There is gold" (Genesis 2:11)
"And the gold there is good
"There are pearls and red agates there" (Gen 2:12)
"The name of the second river is Gihon
"It surrounds the whole land of Cush" (Gen 2:13)
"The name of the third river is Tigris
"It flows east of Assyria
"The fourth river is the Euphrates" (Gen 2:14)
There’s something weird about geography
Hybrid with mythical geography
You will find this often appears in the Bible
"The Lord God will
"Placed in the Garden of Eden
"Make him repair the guard" (Gen 2.15)
This is a good command
That's what you should do
Manage these things
There is a lot of work to be done
It took a whole week
"The Lord God told him to say
"The fruits of all the trees in the garden
"You can eat whatever you want" (Gen 2:16)
"Just the fruit on the tree of good and evil
"You must not eat
"Because you must die the day you eat" (Gen 2:17)
There are a bunch of problems here
People have been confused about this for a long time
God is a weird character in the story of Adam and Eve
If we can't eat this
Why did you put it in the garden at the beginning
This will be a problem
You created us and you told us not to eat it
Obviously very clear
The first thing we will do is eat it
Because people are so natural
If you tell these
People with insatiable curiosity
Said "It's all good here
"And there is a place you can never see"
Then you leave here
And everyone was there trying to figure out what it was
In a blink of an eye, right
We are very curious creatures
So you want to know what God’s intention is here
There is a Gnostic conjecture
The first god
Not a good god
He is a somewhat unconscious evil god
He hopes his creation has no consciousness
So as to prevent them from developing awareness
And here again a higher-level god appeared
He may be in the image of a poisonous snake
The god who lures people to consciousness
This concept was eliminated by classical Christianity very early
Although it has some interesting things
And it takes various forms
Remnants left in the story
For example, think "fallen"
Is a completely tragic point of view
But on the other hand
It is a prerequisite for the greatest event in history
Which is the birth of Jesus
Salvation with mankind
so
Put it this way, it's complicated
Only God knows what he is going to do
This is a good example of that ambivalence
to me
This again shows how smart the people who integrate these stories are
I still think this is almost a miracle
Because you know
If you are just a promoter
You won't keep such complicated things in the text
You will just lose it
Because if you are a promoter
Everything should make sense on the ideological level
God should be good here
So we better delete this sentence
Because something goes in and out of it
And it's not obvious what it is
But people didn't do it
To me it shows that people are doing two things
That they try to
Not careless
They are risking contact with them
And they are very careful about tradition
And trying to figure out what happened
Because otherwise, why should I record these?
Why not simplify them
Or maybe
Attribute these simply to the devil
It’s better than letting God do these things
Much simpler
"The Lord God says
"It's not good for that person to live alone
"I will make him a spouse to help him" (Gen 2:18)
"The wild beasts that the Lord God made with soil
"And all the birds in the sky
"Bring them to that person
"Look at his name
"How that person calls all kinds of living creatures,
"That's its name" (Gen 2:19)
"The man gave all the livestock"
Livestock generally refers to animals
"And the birds in the sky
"The wild beasts are named
"It's just that the person didn't meet
"Spouse helps him" (Gen 2:20)
Here are a few things to guess
First why does God care
What did Adam call these animals
Again the answer seems
Is related to the magic of words
According to the story we know
Humans have
Was created in the image of God
And God uses language
To summon order from chaos
Human beings were created in that image
So there is a resonance here
Although it comes from an independent tradition
This resonance is
Things are not real enough before you name it
This is an interesting thing
And we don’t know exactly where this will extend
The usual situation is
Things often exist in a peculiar underlying form
Form of internal connection
Everything in it is very confusing
Until you point it out and name it
What exactly happened when you named it
It opened itself up from the potential chaos
And turn yourself into
Tangible entities you can oppose
Of course you might say
It's real before you name it
"It was real before you named it."
And "things exist before no one observes"
It's the same thing
When you are not observing things
It is not clear whether things exist
I want to tell you about the weird side of perception
You can find it here in John Wheeler
John Wheeler is a physicist
The cool thing is
If you go out at night
Then I looked up and saw the stars
The photons from this star reach your eyes
This photon may have been roaming for 30 million years
Do you know
This photon from that star
If your eyes don’t receive it here and now
May not be sent
You might think how is this possible
Because this happened 20 million years ago
Actually I don’t know how this is possible
But I know John Wheeler
Do a lot of work to describe in detail
Why this is necessarily true
Wheeler still developed
Physicist with the concept of "Everything comes from bits"
He believes
Potential part of the world
Best to be analyzed as a place for potential information
The role of consciousness is to transform potential information into
Something similar to concrete reality
He is not just making an analogy
One of the basis given by him
The story I told you just now
If the photon doesn’t have a destination
It is impossible to leave where it is
This is complicated and puzzling
Because from the perspective of a beam of light originating from photons
There is no time
There is no distance from one place to another
Of course this seems completely incomprehensible
But from the perspective of a photon
The universe is completely flat
Perpendicular to the direction of photon travel
It exists everywhere at the same time
Not for us
It was 20 million years ago
But for photon, it is everywhere
Anyway, the reason I tell you this is
The relationship between consciousness and reality
Definitely not clear
It's not clear at all
Physicists also argue
The relationship between consciousness and reality
They also argue
What does the phenomenon I just described mean
I really don't have the right to join this argument
Because i am not a physicist
But I read quite Wheeler’s philosophy
As far as I can understand
I also at least understand that this is what he claims
I also know that this assertion is capable of understanding Wheeler’s
Physicists are taken seriously
This is very interesting
Anyway, there is a
Emphasis on the importance of making things real
You know sometimes people don’t name things
Just for them not to become reality
If you have a relationship
Obviously you have
It will have problems
Obviously it will
You actually know
Many times there are things that nobody wants to name
Is hidden
Everyone is thinking
As long as we don’t give it a name, it’s not there
To some extent it is indeed not there
Because you can pretend it's not there
Then get away with it
At least in the short term
But once you give it a name
You gave it the form and no one can ignore it anymore
It's irritating because then you have to deal with it
Or face the consequences
The reason I tell you this is
We have an intuition
Can make things non-existent by not naming things
You name it and it appears very clearly
This is not to say that naming is the only thing that makes it a reality
But it sharpens things and brings it into focus
And gave it boundaries and scope
Whatever God wants to say to Adam
Have enough interest
He asked Adam to name all the animals
This makes them into animals to some extent
There is more important than this for this language story
Roger Brown
Studied this interesting phenomenon
It is related to the relationship between perception and action
Do you know how the child treats
Is a specific animal called a cat
The word cat is as short as the word dog
We can think of cats as multicellular organisms
Because we can see the cells
We can see the molecules we can see the atoms
We can also see the ecosystem that cats belong to
Or broader classification of mammals it belongs to
We can think of it as a unit of perception
But we don't
We observe things at the level of cats
You can tell what people can perceive naturally
Perceptual level
By the way this anyway
It's not determined by social culture
Because these words are usually short
Easy to remember and learned very early
Analysis on this level
It exists in this world
In every possible level of analysis
We perceive it with a specific level of analysis
And the analysis at this level seems to be
At that level, the world is related to our functional utility
Perception at that level
And the naming of that level
Make things at that level a reality
The characteristics of things are
They are not easily separated from other things
They are entangled in all sorts of strange ways
But when we cast our eyes and use language
To point one's direction in the world
We divide things into what we can use
Distinguishable things
Something about this
Somehow make them
Than they were before
The potential to connect with each other is more real
At least this is not the same type of reality
I think even more untrue
I think this is the right way to look at it
Even if it is not completely untrue
It is a resonance
Adam is a little god at this moment
Little God Little Father
And God has done the basic work well
But Adam needs to show up and say
This is a cat
No matter what it is now it is a cat
And that's a dog, that's a sheep
This gives them something similar to actual form
"It's just that the man didn't meet his spouse to help him" (Genesis 2:20)
"The Lord God made him fall asleep and he fell asleep
"So he took off one of his ribs
"Put the flesh together again" (Gen 2:21)
"The Lord God used the ribs taken from the man
"Cause a woman to lead her to that man" (Gen 2:22)
"The man said, "This is the flesh of my bones
"『You can call her a woman
"'Because she was taken out of a man'" (Gen 2:23)
"So people have to leave their parents
"Unite with your wife and become one body" (Gen 2:24)
The last three sentences have a powerful expression
The word "therefore" seems surprising
But here is a command
This is a good command
Because people who don't
Will spend a very painful time in marriage
If you are married or plan to get married
Then you should know this
We tend to fall to our parents for many reasons
The command here is
Once you get married, other things are second-rate
And failing to do this order will make your marriage fall apart
And to me it collapsed, you deserve it
Because it reflects your pathological immaturity
And you are
Unwillingness to escape from parental control
These parents are too in a position of interference
But this command
There is a very profound command
It's complicated
There is a view that Adam was not originally a man
Not a single man
He is more like an androgynous being
In this hermaphrodite being
There are species divided into males and females
Undifferentiated perfection
Part of humanity’s goal is to reunite the two
Restore the original perfect individual
This is actually the spiritual goal of marriage
You can read something from Jung
Jung wrote a lot about this point of view
What a great point of view
I have a couple who went to Sweden to get married
They are from North Alberta
But they inherited the Swedish tradition
They did a cool thing at the wedding
Just when they are about to get married
They put a candle between each other
When they got married
You would think what a candle is
It is the source of light
It is the source of lighting
It is the source of enlightenment
It is the candle you put on the Christmas tree in Europe
It is the light that emerges from the darkness in the cold winter
It is a sign of life in the dark
It is the reappearance of the sun at the darkest and coldest time of the year
This is also symbolic for various complicated reasons
Related to the birth of Christ
So candles are all this
The next question is why do you hold it over the top
Because what is higher than you is what is lower than you
It symbolizes something transcendent
For example, why do you hold it tightly together
Because you should all hold onto the light tightly, right
You should obey the light
You will ask who is leading the marriage
Is light
That's what I mean
You become one together
You are no longer both
It's not about what is good for you or your wife
This is good for marriage
Marriage-related beings
At the beginning
Reorganization of the presence of hermaphrodite
That's what I mean
And all meanings are included in four sentences
All sentences are
Associated with a lot of historical interpretation
It's endless and it's just some of them
It also corrected since the woman was taken from the man
This is also the opposite of the biological process
And subordinate women to men
This is not the meaning of this passage
I don't think this is the meaning of this passage at all
There are other links in this passage
There is a view that
The princess sleeps in "Sleeping Beauty"
And the reason she fell asleep was
You must remember what happened
She has a pair of older parents
Anxious for a child
Like many people now
They only have one child
They don’t want anything bad to happen to their children
It's like this is a miracle
And only one
And she is a princess
So we don't let anything approach her
They held a baptism ceremony
They invited everyone
But they did not invite Mel Fiscent
Melficent is the mother of fear
She is nature itself
She is something that suddenly entered the night
In other words, she is the devil himself
She is everything you don't want your child to meet
So the king and queen said
Then let's not invite her to the baptism ceremony
Want to be beautiful
This is an Oedipus story, right
Oedipus’ mother is that
Ruined their mother by overprotecting her children
So instead of the children
Become stronger by touching this world
Was weakened by excessive protection
In this way, when they are put into the world
They cannot survive
This is the story of "Sleeping Beauty"
This is what the king and queen did
They apologized to Melficent when she showed up
They have a bunch of stupid
Why didn’t you ask her an excuse "We forgot"
I don’t think you will forget this kind of thing
And she seems to have explained
The horror of life
You can’t forget it when you have a child
You might want it to be controlled
But you won't forget it
The key is whether you invite it to the party
The answer is that it all depends on
How ignorant you want your child to become
If you want your child to be ignorant
Then you get the added benefit that they won’t leave home
You can use them for the rest of your tragic life
Instead of leaving them to find something to do
Of course you can retaliate against them
Whenever they have a little bit of you 30 years ago
The impulse to pursue courage
And as soon as you see it develop in your child
Just want to destroy it
This is another interesting thing
This is the story in "Sleeping Beauty"
These are all unpleasant
Everything that happened in the story is unpleasant
Sleeping Beauty is terribly naive
Her parents settled her in the forest
Let the three have no real ability and strength
The hypocritical good old fairy raised her
They are harmless
Then she and the first idiot prince who passed by
Too deep in love
So that when he rode away
She has post-traumatic stress disorder
That's it
Then she walked into the castle extremely excited
Because she and her love in this life
See you for about five minutes, my God
This is the spinning wheel
Which is when the wheel of fortune appears
Stabbed her finger
They tried to get rid of the wheel of fortune and their spikes
But she found it and poked her finger
Fell down unconsciously
But she hopes that she is not surprised at all
She was protected all her life
And very naive
So that her first love relationship was almost fatal
She hopes to sleep and never wake up
This is exactly what actually happened
So she had to wait for the prince to save her
How sexist do you think this story is
Seriously because this is the modern world
Will interpret it
She doesn't need a prince to save her
This is why Disney filmed "Frozen"
This movie is really shocking trash
You can say that the princess does not need the prince to save
But this is a stupid way of looking at the story
Because the prince is not just a man who goes to save a woman
Believe me he has his own problems
There is a whole dragon that needs him to fight
The prince also represents women's own consciousness
Consciousness is often expressed as a masculine symbol in stories
Logos’s point of view is the same
This view refers to
There is no forward brave consciousness
Women themselves fall into unconsciousness and fear
You can understand
A sleeping woman needs a man to wake up
Of course just as men need women to wake up
This is the same as the Dragon Slaying in "Sleeping Beauty"
But it also means that if she is not conscious
She can only lie there to sleep
Like the naive and the cursed
She must wake herself
And pushed her masculine consciousness to the forefront
So that she can survive in the world
Obviously women are doing their best
But this story only shows part
This is also implied by the following view
Ie unless the female is separated from the male
Otherwise she is not a human, she is just a creature
This is part of the story rooted in this
So you don’t want to understand it as patriarchal
You don't want to understand everything in this way
I don't want to repeat
But really we can do better than this
"So people have to leave their parents
"Combine with your wife, and the two will become one" (Gen 2:24)
Another career about marriage is worth knowing
I learned partly from Jung
What did you do when you got married
Very simple
You find someone as bad as yourself
Then torture yourself with this person
Then said we will never leave
No matter what happens
This is great because then you won't run away
The truth is if you can escape
You can't tell the truth
If you tell the truth to others and they don’t run away
Then they are not listening
If there is no one by your side who can't escape
You can't tell the truth to them
This is also one of the purposes of marriage
I bet on you you bet on me
We all know this is a failed bet
But considering the status quo
We are unlikely to find better people
Two things can be drawn here
One is that people always wait to meet the right person
You can think about it so you know it
If you go to a party to find Prince Charming
And he saw you running away without screaming
This means he is not a prince charming at all
It's like an old Nietzsche joke
"If someone loves you
"He will immediately lose his charm in your eyes."
Or Woody Allen-style jokes
"I will never join a club that will allow me to join"
This is something worth thinking about
You will treat yourself to someone who is as imperfect as you
Tied together
This way you may enter a situation where you can really negotiate
You may think you have some problems
I also have some questions
Regardless of the consequences
We are all grasshoppers tied to a rope for the next 50 years
We can either solve these things
Or suffer 50 years
People belong to the kind
Not aware of the severity of this matter
Then these problems will not be solved
You don’t name those things and choose to ignore them
Because you always have a way out
Living with someone else is one thing
Cohabitation before marriage
More likely to divorce than vice versa
the reason is
What are your intentions when you live with someone
Just think about it
So far
You are the best person i can fool
But I want to reserve the right to replace you at any time
If a better person happens to hit me
How can anyone not be offended by this proposal
They will be willing to cooperate
Because they will treat you the same way
That's it
I know you won't promise me
It means you don't take me
Or our relationship is at the highest position
But as long as I can leave when I want
I would also play with you
This is incredible, you might think
It’s too stupid to tie yourself to someone else
Really stupid, no doubt
But it’s better than other options
There are some things you'll never learn without this restraint
Because you can avoid it, you always have a way out
If you can leave, you don't have to tell the truth
It's that simple, you can leave directly
So you don’t have anyone who can be honest with you
These pictures are all representations of "origin"
These are not all Adam
This picture is an ancient Chinese symbol
I remember it was called Fuxi and Nuwa
I think my pronunciation is not accurate enough
But it is really cool
Look at the snake below
They are a bit like DNA symbols
I think it's interesting
They are the embryonic form of the giant snake in the primitive universe
All potential is born from it
And there is a division between male and female
So it's like an unknown predator
This is a way to understand it
The most basic concept of mankind is the unknown predator
Then there are two
The division of basic cognitive elements
Positive and negative
You can see a similar situation in this picture
This picture is from Egypt
Also very old
This giant snake forms the basis of everything
It is divided into Isis Queen of the Underworld
King of Osiris, King of Swan, Pharaoh, King of Order
You are in ancient alchemy symbols
Can see the same thing
I like it because it looks so much like
The little things Harry Potter chased
This is not accidental
Seekers are responsible for chasing this
Win if you catch it
This is really an old idea
I can’t figure out how J.K. Rowling knew
Because this is a very old mysterious symbol
It is called "Circular Chaos" on Google
I searched for "circular chaos" on Google
Only relevant references can be found on my page
So I don’t know how Rowling came up with it
Although I know she has read a lot of ancient documents
"If you catch this thing in the meta game,
"You will win all games"
The above idea is completely correct
This is what is called Quidditch's theme
This is "potential"
God is in this potential
Created the world at the beginning of time
And what emerged from it was a certain
Turi, that's the dragon
Fighting another dragon
This is partly the snake in the Garden of Eden
And then it also showed masculine and feminine
Potential predator unknown positive and negative
This is like the evolution history of human cognitive consciousness
Single manifestation of
This is very powerful
And this is an ideal image
This is a union of the sun and the moon
A superbiological hermaphrodite
This is also Adam and Eve at the beginning of time
Before the "fall" happened
This is also the purpose of marriage
This is a sacrament
Is shown in all these images
The wide range of images that can be included in this concept
Is totally incredible
These are some more classic forms of expression
About Eve being taken out of Adam’s body
This is a very cool sentence
"At that time, the husband and wife were naked
"Not ashamed" (Gen 2:25)
I wrote this sentence because someone
Surprised that Adam and Eve are not ashamed
Otherwise, why would they point it out
There are two things implied here
For the first time, human beings were naked
They are not ashamed
The second period is now
Humans are ashamed when they are naked
The question is how nudity and shame are linked together
In the classic interpretation of the story of Adam and Eve
The connotative meaning of sex often appears
I think it's related to being naked
But I don’t think it’s that simple
Right my daughter
She might be because of me in this lecture
Get angry at revealing it
When my daughter was a child
Never worry about being naked
Whether to wear clothes or not is the same to her
But when my son was three years old
But has paid great attention to privacy
The door of his bedroom is always closed
Same for bathroom
It’s like saying "Get out"
These things seem to happen autonomously
We have two children
One is very privacy-conscious and the other is not
I don't think
The occurrence of this situation has a lot to do with us
It’s a magical process for my son to become self-aware
This kind of self-consciousness does appear in
In children around three years old
We usually think at this time
Maybe let the kids play around naked on the beach
Not a very good idea
In some cases children are naked in public
Usually no problem
We would consider it acceptable
Why i don't know
Why is nudity gradually becoming unacceptable
Obviously it has to do with sex
But this is a very complicated phenomenon
Nudity is a very complicated thing
First of all, humans are a bit strange
Because compared to most animals
We have very little body hair
We don't know why
Some people think that when humans first wandered in Africa
Lost hair
Humans are really good at running
We can chase animals until they fall
A good-sized human
Can run a horse to death in a week
We really can run
There are many of our ancestors
For example, the Kalahari bushmen are still doing this
They will chase animals until they are exhausted
But these bushmen are safe and sound
They sometimes use poisonous arrows to kill animals
But they can exhaust them just by chasing them
We have great endurance
If you want to run around in the desert
Then we need to be able to dissipate heat in time
So we don’t have any hair. This is an explanation
Buckminster Fowler has an interesting explanation for this
He believed that at some point in our evolution,
We have been by the water for a long time
We are like "fish apes" like fish apes
We like to stay on the beach
A lot of food there
We also like swimming
Us as land animals
Really good at swimming
And we are the same as some marine life
The tears you shed when you cry are salty
Women have a layer of subcutaneous fat
This is the same as some marine life
It's weird that our feet
Good at slapping in the water
Although we can also walk with them
So he thinks
Maybe this adaptation is to live in the water
Just like seals and other animals
We are kind of alive back to the ocean but not quite so
Anyway, it’s interesting to have Mao gone
It does expose us to the environment
But animals with fur are not like this
And we are upright
This is strange because most animals are not
They are all on all fours
Make their fragile parts
Are protected and not exposed to sight
Of course when you stand naked
Your physical and mental qualities are being painfully displayed
People often complain about this
If you look at the feminist strategy
For example, they make a fuss about the concept of "beauty"
Women suffering from eating disorders can be directly attributed to
On the cover of the magazine
Too many beauties printed
Even if the people buying these magazines are women
They are attracted by these magazines
They feel good when they buy
If the stimulus is negative
That women would avoid these magazines
Instead of buying them
So as a theory
It's very bad
But it is
Examples of "beauty standards make people feel ashamed"
Even if you are not ugly now
It will definitely become ugly at some stage in the future
This is a difficult thing to deal with
Knowing that I can be the perfect look
Even I used to be perfect
But this state will not last long
Or never become perfect is a painful thing
I think it is more painful for women
Because women are more often men
Comment on age and fertility
This is the result of discussion from the perspective of evolution
Men are more often women
Evaluate in terms of socioeconomic status
Both situations are harsh
No matter how you know that you are exposed to
To all aspects of your life
Before the harshest judges
Is a terrible thing
And if you are not wearing clothes
This judgment will be further amplified
To a certain extent clothing plays a protective role
But the bigger role of clothing is just to prevent others
Have always been harsh on you
It can have such an impact
So this story proves
We were not like that at a certain time
Animals are not like that
So the inference that "we are not like that"
Seems reasonable
But in a certain period
This situation has changed
"At that time, the husband and wife were naked
"Not ashamed" (Gen 2:25)
"The Jehovah God made
"Only snakes are more cunning than all the living creatures in the field
"The snake said to the woman, "Does God really say
"'You are not allowed to eat
""Are the fruits on all the trees in the garden?" (Genesis 3:1)
I like this print
I can't remember who painted this
Who is it
Doray is right
It was Duo Lei who made the engraving illustrations for "Paradise Lost"
Really beautiful
This side is Satan and this side is a snake
Of course in the "Genesis" story
Satan and the snake are strangely linked
It's hard to clarify
In the story of Adam and Eve
There is no indication
The snake that tempted Eve is also Satan
Is the initiator of all evil
As for how these two stories are tangled together
I think i know the answer
I will reveal it for you tonight
But it really took me a long time to figure it out
It's really wonderful
I can't believe people figure it out
It's incredibly colorful
This is a hint to this idea, right
There is a close relationship between these two things
In short, snakes are more cunning than all creatures in the world
Cunning is a funny word
This is the explanation in the Oxford English Dictionary
We will enlarge the word slightly
This is exactly what you did in the analysis of Jung’s dream
You will pay attention to dreams
Implied meaning of some concepts
Cunning "Describes the actions of humans or animals, etc.
"Cunning, cunning, cunning, unfaithful"
This is very mysterious and low-key, right
It is not easy to find
"Describe the appearance or gaze is cunning, sneaky and sneaky"
"Describe people who are experienced to be professional and smart"
"Describe a piece of art, machinery, etc.
"Ingenious, unique and sophisticated production or design"
I think until now
These terms are derived from snake
I think they are very cool
And the physiological structure is very clever
They are eye-catching
But at the same time it’s not easy to detect
"Describe one that contains
"The nature of obscure distinctions or subtle ideas
"Profound and hard to understand"
"Describe a person’s mental and intellectual activities
"Characterized by wisdom and insight
"He has the ability to discern and is very shrewd"
This is really interesting
Because Milton’s Satan is very intelligent
And this happens often
Bad guys are often evil scientists
You see the same in the Lion King
Scar is a smart character
An arrogant and deceitful but intelligent
It's not stupid at all
It is not a wise man but it is that
The evil voice that always whispers in the ears of the lion king
This is related to the inner pride of the wise
Catholics have been warning mankind for centuries
Don't be proud of human wisdom
This partly caused
The split between Catholicism and science
Although if you look at the history
You will find that the Catholic idea is exaggerated
The idea is
Talented people have a special ability
And it is the highest angel in the kingdom of God
This is how Milton describes it
But it can also be bad
Because intellect can be because of own existence
And achievement and become conceited
It will fall in love with its own results
When you are occupied by ideology
This happens too
Because what you end up with is the dogma created by humans
In the words of Solzhenitsyn
"You are completely controlled by it
"You believe it is 100% correct"
It ends all transcendental things
So this is an implicit factor of intellect
Symbolically linked with the snake in the Garden of Eden
"Describes keen insight such as sense, touch, etc."
"Including that you can feel subtle or subtle differences
"Especially those differences that are too subtle to distinguish or analyze
"Also almost imperceptible and elusive."
"Describe the thickness or width is very thin and thin"
"Subtle things and scarce things"
This kind of thing hardly exists
"The woman said to the snake
""We can eat the fruit from the trees in the garden (Genesis 3:2)
"'Only the fruit of the tree in the garden
"『God once said
"『You must not eat or touch
""Lest you die"" (Genesis 3:3)
"The snake said to the woman, "You don't necessarily die (Genesis 3:4)
"'Because God knows the day you eat
"『The eyes are bright
""As God can know good and evil" (Genesis 3:5)
Cunning, subtle, is this a good story?
In this way it immediately hints
"You can't believe in God"
It's cunning
Then it said "and God is trying to deceive you"
"And God did this out of jealousy"
"And God doesn't want you to know what he knows
"It's not good to let you know."
"And God is lying to you
"Because you won't die anyway."
"If you eat it is contrary to what was warned before
"Your eyes will brighten and nothing more
"You will become like God, knowing good and evil."
This sounds really good
And what does Eve know?
No wonder she is so easily affected by rhetoric
It's also fun
Because God warned Adam and Eve
Don't eat that damn fruit
But they never promised that they would not eat
They did not guarantee that they were just warned
Should they obey
How obedient do you want your child to be
You hope they are submissive enough
So as not to get hurt
But not obedient enough
So that they can break into the sky
Do something brave
Break some rules
Learn something
This is a very contradictory story
Anyway, the snake won this round
Eve listened to what the snake said
The same set of pictures
We have Adam and Eve
We have this tree we have this weird snake
It appears as a dragon like a sphinx
And is associated with the tree
The snake is always associated with the tree
God knows we have done this for tens of millions of years
Arboreal primates
There are three main types of our main natural enemies
Snake, raptor, big cat
So the snake is related to the tree
It's been a long long time
The lesson the snake teaches people is
You better be alert
Otherwise the things you don't like will hurt you
So who is the easiest to follow snakes?
That will be eve
The reason is that Eve has offspring
And for snakes there is nothing more delicious than children
Eve's uneasiness and neuroticism are completely justified
They are more likely to have these qualities than men and women
And the difference is very obvious
This exists in many cultures
And first appeared in puberty
According to our current understanding
Part of the reason is that women are more vulnerable to sexual assault
Women are also smaller
In case of physical conflict
Body size to urinate can be a weakness
More importantly, why do we assume
The human female’s nervous system changes
To adapt to her health
Why don't we assume
Changes in the nervous system of human women
To adapt to the parent-child relationship between her and her child
Because if it weren't the case, the babies would die
You might think
Are more prone than men and women
Depression and anxiety
This is an unimaginable heavy burden
By the way, this also exists in a cross-cultural environment
This also appeared at the beginning of adolescence
The most noticeable difference is in Scandinavia
Some people think that these characteristics are formed by social culture
But in fact, it's not
But this is for a reason, also in puberty
Sexual differences between men and women began to appear
Men's upper body is more powerful
Much stronger than women
So this makes men much more dangerous
Human’s instinctive defense mechanism is boxing
Like a kangaroo
There are other animals that can also punch
Chimpanzees can too
But when humans strike, their power is concentrated on the upper body and shoulders
So women cannot compete with men in the battle
She has every reason to be nervous
Especially when women are particularly vulnerable to sexual assault
And she must be in a long time
Take care of a fragile baby who is extremely dependent on her
In addition, women are more nervous and uncomfortable than men
The empirical literature on this point is clear
It is associated with emotional instability
Because it's actually an unpleasant emotion
Who wants to be uncomfortable
If I am very afraid of making a fool of myself when I talk to you on stage
Then suddenly I won’t be able to talk to you
What I will do is always think about myself
And all my shortcomings and mistakes
Fall into one's heart
Although this personality trait is a great talent
But it's not pleasant
It is mainly associated with anxiety
So Eve has every reason to pay attention to snakes.
I read a story this week
The bad thing is that I don’t remember which tribe it was about
But I added a footnote about this in my new book
These are people living in jungle tribes
5% of adults have been attacked by pythons
And a large number of children were killed by pythons
Snake predation is no joke
It shapes our past in evolutionary history
And it still happens frequently in many areas
We have adapted to the existence of snakes
Anthropologist Lynn Isbel points out
We are very good at spotting camouflage patterns on snakes
Especially in the lower half of our vision
There is evidence that
Humans have such a keen vision
In other words, our eyes become brighter
Partly because we have co-evolved with snakes
We learn to recognize them
At the expense of our brains grow up together
You need a lot of brain capacity to see
The result of human brain growth is
One day we woke up and found the future
The future is where all snakes may live
Instead of where they are now
These same images are very interesting
In this picture, the god of death appears on the tree
With snake and fruit
The fruit also looks interesting
I already said
There is a strong correlation between the food you eat and the information
This is a conceptual connection
Is also an actual connection
And we can distinguish colors
The question is why
The answer is that we have evolved
You can distinguish ripe fruits with your eyes
In the story of Adam and Eve
Humans gain vision through snakes and fruits
It turns out to be correct
Great, right?
So you think that for men
What role does a woman play in a relationship
First of all they make men uncomfortable
Let us never forget this
I want to talk about the main role of women in the relationship with men
Just to make them feel uncomfortable
Men don't like that much
And nothing is more disturbing than being rejected
Why is he rejected
Obviously because of mother nature
Telling you in the image of that woman
"You are pretty good to be friends
"But there is no special reason for your genetic material
"Be spread and continue into the future"
Men feel uncomfortable with being made by women
Not happy at all, right
This is between men and women
The main source of ongoing tension
It's not surprising
But there is another situation
It’s pretty cool and very interesting
We and the chimpanzee were around 600 years ago
Differences appeared after the common ancestor advanced
Here are the reasons at least to some extent
Female chimpanzees are treated equally when it comes to mating
They mate with any male chimpanzee when in heat
Human women would not
When a female chimpanzee is in heat
Any male has a chance
High-status male chimpanzees drive away competitors
So the male chimpanzee with the highest status
Will be more likely to leave offspring
But it’s not the female chimpanzee’s choice
Humans are not like this
Human women often "marry high"
This also exists in different cultural regions
This is also widespread in Scandinavia
There is a little attenuation but not much attenuation
Women usually marry men at a higher level of dominance
And men will marry women at a lower level of dominance
Must be like this
Because it has to be like this. If one goes up and the other goes down
The socioeconomic status of a woman
Has little effect on her attractiveness to men
The socioeconomic status of a man
Is the main determinant of his attractiveness to women
And it doesn’t mean his wealth
This has been proven
But refers to his ability to produce and share
This is much better than wealth
Wealth will disappear but this ability to produce and share
Is a more important factor
Then why not choose on this basis
Especially when women have to have babies
And babies make women more dependent
Women are only from an evolutionary perspective
Look at it logically
Who has the ability to reach out for help at critical moments
It’s no surprise that women make strong demands on men
The problem is that women are more "high-married"
Humans evolved more quickly than chimpanzees
This selection pressure exerted by women on men
Affected the development of our entire species
Two things happened as far as I know
Men compete for ability
So the male hierarchy is a mechanism
Push the best people to the top
Is indeed the same as the meaning of the system itself
Then its effect will be due to
Women marry to the top of the ranks and doubly significant
The most capable men are more likely to leave offspring
This seems to be the reason for the expansion of our cortex
This kind of expansion during the evolutionary period
Happened very quickly
"So the woman saw that the fruit of that tree was good for food
"Also pleasing to the eyes and lovable
"It can make people wise
"Just pick the fruit and eat it
"Give it to her husband and her husband to eat too" (Gen 3:6)
Oh yes, women share food
This is a very strange thing
Because most creatures don’t share food
If you are a wolf
And gain something from the hunt
You will fill yourself
The leading animal will eat first
If there is left
Subordinate animals can also eat
But humans are not like this
We share food
And you can imagine how this behavior evolved
Many females share food with their children
Understanding from the perspective of evolution
It's not difficult
Knowing that you are not just sharing food with your kids
Like sharing with your partner
This is another way for you to attract a spouse
It’s like saying that we will be together better than living alone
This is the part of sharing fruits
What about the uncomfortable part
This is part of the bargaining
I will wake you up
Partly because you need to be woken up
Partly because I have a baby that needs to be taken care of
So you better wake up
In exchange I will give you some food
In response we will form a team
This is the agreement between people
This is why we will more or less
Practice monogamy
Which is why we will more or less
Pair and combine
This is why this kind of marriage-like thing
Universal to humans
This exists in different cultural regions
You can find exceptions but who cares
Who really cares
Look at this huge model
Well, the result of having a bigger brain is
We become very dependent
And it took us a long time to adapt
Because we need a relatively stable family bond
This is basically what we have evolved
It is impossible to achieve this without disturbing men
For male creatures
Why not let the female get pregnant and go away
Really why
This is what we need to consider
Men abandon their children
Not something difficult to understand
But the man insisted on staying
This is incomprehensible
You just need to look at the animal kingdom
The easiest and easiest thing
Always the most likely to happen
So those exceptional long-term commitments need to be explained
"Just pick the fruit and eat it."
"Give it to her husband and her husband to eat too" (Genesis 3:6)
"The eyes of both of them brightened up" (Gen 3:7)
Implied that they were closed before
"I knew I was naked
"Take the leaves of the fig tree
"Weave a skirt for myself" (Genesis 3:7)
This is so interesting
Their eyes opened
This shows that they are different from the beginning
No matter what kind of people God created
They were blind at first
The blindness mentioned here is not blind in the usual sense
They are not walking around in the Garden of Eden
Hit the tree with one head
But refers to "blindness" in the abstract sense
This "blindness" is eliminated by what just happened
What just happened
At the same time make them aware that they are naked
What does "bright eyes" mean
What does it mean to know that you are naked?
It means you realize that you are vulnerable
What people found is this
It's like saying
We might get hurt like this
It’s like you are one of a group of zebras
There is a group of lions lying on the grass near here
And you don't care
Because they are lions lying down
The lying lion is not a problem for you
When he stands up
It becomes a big problem when you are ready to hunt
You are not smart enough to tell
When the Lions lie down
Stand up and start hunting
So you didn’t build a fortress to keep the lion out
You are just eating grass carelessly
You are not alert
But humans are different
Humans awakened and they found
I am vulnerable
And it will always be so fragile and will follow you
Human beings realize that their vulnerability is eternal
What happened after
The first thing they do is put on clothes
When you are naked
What do you do when you want to protect yourself from various threats
Obviously look around you are all wearing clothes
why?
We did this for a long, long time
At least since tens of thousands of years ago
In fact, how much you can track
When did clothing develop
Because you can attach it to clothes instead of hair
Of lice do DNA test
We have a clear understanding of when clothing will appear
Also know that there are different types of clothing
This is amazing
But the point is that Adam and Eve was naked at first
It's not so good for them to think of this
Because we are fragile
Their eyes are already bright
So they have self-awareness
They found their vulnerability
The first thing they did
Took the first step of civilization
Protect yourself with things that already exist in the world
You protect yourself from the dangerous world
Stay away from prying eyes
This is Lynn Isbel's book
A passage from "Why We See So Clear"
"Temptation from Eve
"To the mighty Thor was killed by the snake venom
"The snake's figure always runs through
"Over time and various cultures
"It is considered a symbol of disaster and pain"
"Snakes are notorious all over the world
"Whether in religious mythology or folklore
"All highlight our connection with snakes
"But why
"Since there are only a few of us
"I have encountered a snake myself"
"This book gives a surprising answer
"The answer lies in the unique influence of snakes on the evolution of primates."
"Isbel told us
"The predation pressure of snakes on us
"It makes us sharper vision and bigger brain
"The ultimate reason
"This may be the evolution of primates and humans
"A crucial step"
This has been proven recently
Psychologists have known for a long time
People’s fear of snakes can be acquired
But they found that a group of primate neurons
Thalamic-occipital neuron
Has a special purpose
This is a very old sensory system
"The thalamus-occipital neuron group is neurobiologically confirmed
"Our past evolution is to find snakes quickly"
This is a 2013 study
So the snake did wake us up
Color vision is evolved by primates in order to adapt to eating fruits
It seems that women want to attract men
And it’s no coincidence to dress yourself up like a ripe fruit
And this is not because of social culture
"It's a cool breeze, the Lord God is walking in the garden
"The man and his wife heard the voice of God
"Hidden in the trees in the garden
"Hide from the face of the Lord God" (Genesis 3:8)
This passage is very interesting
What is the meaning
Before humanity awakens
Before I found myself naked and vulnerable
There is no need for humans to avoid God
Are they now avoiding God?
Are they naked and fragile
Let's think about it
Think about it
Imagine you have the ability to live
Sincere, brave and frank
Let's imagine
Then think about why you wouldn’t do that
Is it because of fear and shame
How they stop you
Imagine we have been to a
The idea of ​​being sincere, brave and frank is a bit similar to
We already know from the story
Walk with God in the Garden of Eden
What prevents people from doing this
What prevents people from hiding
Because they found their shortcomings
They looked at and felt
If everything around me is a mess
So a creature like me
How to survive in this world
Think about what you are avoiding
You go home and sit on your own bed for five minutes
Ask yourself what you are avoiding
God will gradually appear in your mind
Thousands of answers
Now let's see why you are running away
No doubt you are running away
People are running away from this is nothing new
This is the horror of this story
Every morning we wake up and think
Gosh look at this place
There are many tricky troubles
And we ourselves are in trouble
And we failed to live what we should be
So we hid
This is what this story is about
People wake up with self-awareness
Found his own vulnerability
This vulnerability keeps them in hiding
In order to escape from fulfilling his sacred destiny
Completely correct
I really like this part of the story
This part is very interesting,
We can use this part to relax
"Jehovah God called the man to say
""Where are you"" (Genesis 3:9)
"He said, "I heard your voice in the garden
"『I’m scared
""Because I am naked"" (Genesis 3:10)
There is no doubt that this is why he hid
""I hid"" (Genesis 3:10)
"The Lord said,'Who told you that you were naked
"『Can you eat it?
"'I told you not to eat
""The fruit on the tree?" (Genesis 3:11)
This is the glorious moment of Adam after the "fall"
"The man said, "That woman
"『The woman you gave me to live with me
"'She gave me the fruit from that tree,
"'I'll eat it"' (Genesis 3:12)
This is the sad man
In addition, some modern feminists think
The story of Adam and Eve
Portray Eve as a villain against humanity
Because she ate the forbidden fruit against the will of God
Yes
Looks like she fell first
Seduced her husband again
Make them all worse
Of course Adam was so stupid that he ate it immediately
This means
She was braver than her husband and awakened first
I think Adam is really in this story
A sad creature
Let’s review what he did in a few words
First of all this is not what I did, it was given to me by Eve
Then he blamed God
"It's the woman you gave me"
"She gave me the fruit and I ate it."
It sounds like Adam is completely innocent
Except now
He is not only naked, rebellious and cowardly shameful
He is still a crying slander behind his back
He turned his back on Eve without hesitation
I blamed God
This is true
You go online to see when men hold resentment against women
Comments written on women
So funny
"It's not my fault, it's those little bitches who smashed"
"It's not that I'm wrong, it's them"
Not only that, they also blamed others
This is exactly the same as the story shows
Really sad and contemptible
"The Lord God said to women
"'What are you doing?'
"The woman said
""The snake tempted me and I ate it" (Genesis 3:13)
Well at least she has an excuse
First it is a snake
Actually
We have already said that snakes are very cunning
Secondly, the snake gradually evolved into Satan himself
Very insidious and cunning
So Eve fell into the snake trap
This is indeed blameworthy
But Biyadan’s excuse is so good that I don’t know where it is.
"The Lord God said to the snake
"『Since you did this
"『You will be cursed
"'More than all livestock and beasts
"'You must walk on your belly
""Eat soil for life"" (Genesis 3:14)
Incidentally
A snake is a lizard without legs
You should all understand
"'I want you and the woman to be enemies
"'Your descendants and women's descendants are also hostile to each other
"'A woman's descendant will hurt your head
"'You will hurt his heel'" (Genesis 3:15)
I like these two paintings very much
Exquisite
By the way
Regardless of the religious background
What do you see
The eternal mother holds her child
Protect him from snakes
See it right below the picture
Crocodile snake
These are the animals that have preyed on us for the past 600,000 years
It’s the protection of the mother of eternity that keeps us alive today
That's why this is a sacred painting
I prefer the picture on the right
It looks like the moon below
Eve stepped on this reptile
This form is very old
I may have shown it to you before
But I think this is really great
She emerged from a ring in the sky
This symbolizes eternal reincarnation in her
you can say so
This eternal reincarnation
Is a prototype
It implies that she is being born
Behind this are some musical instruments
What the painter wants to show is
The intricacies of the great life forms of life
Protect our mother from being born from the background
Protect the child forever
Keep them from being prey
How can this not be a sacred sight
If you don't think so
Then it's not a matter of painting
It's your problem
"To the woman again" (Genesis 3:16)
Now God just lists the consequences of stealing the forbidden fruit
As if you were asleep
After you wake up
These things will happen
"'I will increase your pain of pregnancy
"'You have to suffer more when you give birth to children
"'You must adore your husband
""Your husband will rule you"" (Genesis 3:16)
God still didn't say he should
But that he is going to
why
"You will suffer more when you give birth to children" (Genesis 3:16)
When your brain evolves big enough
You will find
Having a baby is never easy anymore
And then people created something
Something based on faith
This can be said to be one of the curses to humans
So this is the punishment Eve received for awakening
"Said to Adam
"『Since you obeyed your wife,
"'Eat the fruit of the tree that I told you not to eat
"'The earth will be cursed for your sake
"'You will toil for life
""You can eat from the ground"" (Genesis 3:17)
What does this passage mean
This is the emergence of the concept of "work"
"'The earth will give you thorns and thistles
"'You also want to eat the vegetables in the field'" (Genesis 3:18)
It defines the concept of work
What is the difference between human behavior and animals
jobs
What does work mean
Means you sacrifice the present for the future
Why people do this
Because they are aware of their vulnerability
They have awakened
Since then
Humans can never go back to the subconscious heaven
I don’t care how many problems you solve to make sure
Pingshun today
No matter how much work you do
New problems will follow
You can never work until they are completely resolved
Everything you do now is in fear of the future
This is the price of awakening
This is Paradise Lost
Human history begins
This is what this story is going to tell us
"'You must be sweaty to make ends meet
"'Until you return
"『Because you came from the soil
"『You are dust
""Return to the dust" (Genesis 3:19)
"Adam named his wife Eve
"Because she is the mother of all beings" (Genesis 3:20)
"Jehovah God for Adam and his wife
"Use leather to make clothes for
"Wear them" (Genesis 3:21)
By the way, this was painted by William Blake
"The Lord God says
"『That person is already similar to us
"『Can know good and evil
"'I'm afraid he reaches out now
"'Pick the fruit of the tree of life and eat
""Live forever"" (Genesis 3:22)
I'll talk about these two pictures next week
"The Lord God sent him out of the Garden of Eden
"Cultivate the soil from which he came from" (Genesis 3:23)
"So kicked him out
"Again east of the Garden of Eden
"Set up cherubim and a flaming sword turning around
"Keep guarding the path of the tree of life" (Genesis 3:24)
Let's talk a little bit more
I think this is why
Adam and Eve were tempted by a snake
So I ate the forbidden fruit
Wake them up
They realized that they were naked
Realize that I am vulnerable
Aware of the future
Realized that I will die
Realize that I have to work
Realized the difficulty of fertility
Ever since lost the subconscious garden of Eden
All of this makes sense
But what is the perception of good and evil
What does the knowledge of good and evil mean to them
In Mesopotamian mythology
Goddess of Chaos, Diamat, according to what she can imagine
Worst monster image
Created mankind with Jin Gu's blood
Their thoughts are in the deepest part of human nature
There are cracks ripped by the devil
This is what they think
These stories are all born in a similar context
So open your eyes
Aware of their vulnerability
What does it have to do with the knowledge of good and evil?
I thought about it very seriously
I must say
I thought about it for 20 years
Because I know there is something in these stories
I can't unify them
at the same time
I am also reading the literature
I want to tell you an unfortunate fact
If you need high-energy warning
I will give you one now
Trust me
I never give people warning easily
The things I want to tell you you will never forget
This is what Unit 731 did in China
731 was a Japanese army during World War II
What i know is
During the Second World War
Did something pretty creepy
Really outrageous
What they do is
Gather the prisoners in one place
Hold their arms completely
Then take the captive out
Pour boiling water on the captive's arm
Repeat this until the captive is separated
They claim to do this for research
"How to heal soldiers' frostbite"
Unless you want to have a nightmare
Don't care about Unit 731
This is Unit 731
This is human
Someone patted his head and came up with this idea
Some people implemented it recklessly
What is the knowledge of good and evil
This is the point
You know you are vulnerable
No other animal knows
You know what will hurt you
Now that you know you are vulnerable and what will hurt you
You know what can hurt others
Once you know what can hurt others
You can use the method of hurting others
Because you can distinguish good from evil
Snakes are really tricky
Because of something
If we know the result in advance
We might not want to try
But once humans have self-awareness
Aware of his nakedness
He has the ability to do evil
From here on this situation is known to the world
The rest of the story is
There are already snakes in the world, right
If you are a primate living in a tree
You know snakes can prey on primates
It's bad
So you want to stay alert to snakes
So your brain grows
You can think about it
There are more than just snakes on the tree
The tree is where the snake lives
Why don't we get down from the tree
Hunt them and then
Get rid of them
They are kind of like potential snakes
So the snake becomes a potential snake
The loop you use to handle this is the same
You have to get rid of the snake
Just like St. Patrick drove the snake out of Ireland
No more snakes
Here is heaven
No no no no
Things will not develop like this
You find someone has become a snake
Suppose you live in a tribe
You will have hostile tribes
You have to protect yourself from them, right
Maybe your power has grown
You defeated all the enemies
What will happen next
Snakes will appear from within you
Even if you eliminate all external enemies
Built a big city
The enemy will continue to emerge from within you
The snake not only represents the snake in the Garden of Eden
Not just a realistic snake
Not just your enemy
Snake may be your friend
Because your friend might betray you
There is something worse than this
You might betray yourself
Even if you get rid of all the snakes outside
You yourself are always a snake that cannot be eliminated
No one knows why
This is why Christians want to put
The snake in the Garden of Eden is connected with Satan
How clever this is
Think about it
Who is my enemy
Yes it's a snake
But you have to know if you are
Primates inhabiting trees are good for you
You are one after 6 million years
Precision humans born with extra evolution
You spent a lot of effort to solve
"What is the greatest enemy of mankind?"
Human nature is inherently evil
This is the symbol of Satan
This symbol means
Just like there are logos in the world
The truth at the beginning of time
Summoned from the chaos
There is also an opposing spirit in the world
An anti-purpose brother
Like Cain did to Abel
We will talk about this next week
It's all against you
This opposing spirit is completely
Driven by evil beliefs and desire for destruction
It has a reason to act
This is the content of the next story
The story of Cain and Abel is in a paragraph
Except for the weird claims of Christian mystics
This opposing spirit began to appear for the first time
It and the serpent of eden
Have identity with the initiator of all evil